<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Uonai</title>
 <link href="http://localhost:4000/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://localhost:4000/"/>
 <updated>2018-12-31T15:38:39-06:00</updated>
 <id>http://localhost:4000</id>
 <author>
   <name></name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>A Manifesto for Post-Veganism</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2018-10-08-post-veganism/"/>
   <updated>2018-10-08T01:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/post-veganism</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;At some point the Veganism sizzled out and died in the Western metropolis. We now have aisles dedicated to our cause, brands emerging from NYC to Silicon Valley custom-tailoring their products to suit our needs: Daiya, Soylent, Oatly, Beyond Meat. There are too many to count.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Internet commerce helps to deliver our exact preferences to our doorstep, we can set and forget and have a custom Vegan diet delivered week after week. Convenience stores are no different with 7-11’s now stocking all of the essentials for Vegans on the go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Veganism isn’t a reactionary choice now so much as an identity. All of the footwork is done. Veganism is now a feature to add onto your existing lifestyle. Instead of choosing one item, you choose another. Protest is an option, but is in no way required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what we worked for though. A world where it would be easy to abstain from animal products. Granted, some wanted to eliminate all animal suffering, but many of us knew the Vegan utopia would be impossible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All utopias are based on contradictions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Veganism was the beginning of modern identity politics. The movement was reactionary by nature, letting us branch into radically different lifestyles to see how we could change the world and how to militarize our tribes for good. PETA, Mercy For Animals and the like are now Institutionalized Group Identity, small corporations growing larger each day, and it’s only a matter of time before they forget their roots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we near the end of the era of identity politics, we will also end the era of old-Veganism, Veganism-as-lifestyle-identity, Veganism held against our enemies as a bludgeon and a badge. Critics have good reason to frown upon us now, as the movement becomes in many regards a caricature of itself. Take a look at the YouTube vegan community and it resembles in many ways Jersey Shore. This is not a bad thing, it is what it is and invites criticism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have nothing left to react to, we’ve won the game and the Western metropolis has made Veganism incredibly accessible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what comes next? Let’s look at the history of the movement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What did Veganism originally stand for? It was a movement that cut through the bullshit. That denied everything we had been told, critiquing all movements and seeking to find only truth. It meant setting aside political divides, viciously critiquing capitalist institutions, and moving en-mass toward a shared goal. And due to all of this, we achieved it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We made Veganism accessible to all and a force that couldn’t be ignored. This may be the first and last success of the era of identity politics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what can we learn from the successes/failures of the Vegan movement, to create a Vegan Movement 2.0?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Critique everything that can be critiqued.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Strive to live ethically without harming animals (human or otherwise) in the process.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make your movement accessible to all.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Avoid labels at all costs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>XXVIII</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2018-06-06-XXVIII/"/>
   <updated>2018-06-06T01:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/XXVIII</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I turned twenty eight today. They say if you don’t celebrate your birthday, no one else will celebrate it for you. My way of celebrating is reflecting, I guess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking back, this may have been my best year yet. I’m surrounded by my closest friends, some at proximity, some at a distance. My fiancee and I are planning our wedding. I’ve changed jobs, and now I’m for the most part inspired at all hours of the day.  I traveled to Kenya, India, and Aruba to work and to experience. It was the first time I’d left the states.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a time that I thought getting older would mean the end of inspiration. That as I aged, I would lose the energy to create. That I’d fade into the shadows and rot behind a desk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That may happen eventually, but I’m happy to say that I’m not rotting yet. I may actually have more focus and drive now than I’ve ever had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve grown a love for the process of creating this year, more than ever. Every day I look forward to what I’m going to do rather than what I’m going to make. I’m focusing more and more on the details that go into what I’m making rather than the final product itself. The final product never ends up what I expect it to be. So I’m finding that the time spent building it (writing it, drawing it, etc.) is the most rewarding time in the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a series of projects planned that I’m actively contributing to. Some projects are tools to make the complex simple. Others are grandiose ideas that may never reach fruition. You’ll hear more about Codex, Tiktaki, Xumske, Omeyocan, and Uppakoma soon. On a wider scale, I’ll be contributing more to the P2P community, and mesh IoT networking. These are my passions as a programmer and I’ll be pursuing them with whatever force I have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of you may have noticed I’ve been difficult to reach this year. I took a step back from social networking to get my head around why I was doing it and how I could make it more positive. I maintain very few social platforms now, and the ones I do maintain, I care deeply about and I don’t plan on leaving. With the changes I’ve made this year, lately I’ve been having a great time on the internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turning twenty-eight means that I’m well on my way to thirty. Thirty used to seem like a big milestone. I’m not worried about passing that milestone now. I’ve found my passions. I’ve set my private and public goals. I’m inspired and full of energy to create work.  As long as I’m contributing to the communities I support, aging doesn’t seem relevant.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Haunted Web</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2018-06-03-the-haunted-web/"/>
   <updated>2018-06-03T01:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/the-haunted-web</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When I tell ghost stories of my time in The South, I talk of old hospitals and ancient beaches. The subtle coldness and fear of the experiences that I had. Transient feelings never quite solidified as memories. Never internalized to a point that I could reflect on them in a deep way. Lingering somewhere in me, both as part of my story, yet never a part of me or of the physical world for that matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ghosts exist, I think, somewhere between our physical world and our mental reality. They surround us and walk the margins of experiences we can’t comprehend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a stark similarity between old Southern mansions and the modern web. I’ve noticed for the past few years the subtle coldness and fear of every day experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I look to the social web now, the a-temporal electronic monolith. Minute-by-minute breathing the data formed from our concurrent shared experiences. An algorithmic life force churning away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ask anyone who has recently tried to escape from stalkers, criminals, and mobs to define the web. The web is horror manifest as reality. The web is an eye and a voice for actors that seek infinite vision and reach. The web is no longer contained to devices. It’s a geographic net overlaying reality. An algorithmic structure grinding and shifting reality as it changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The web paints our days and nights, it constructs our dreams and nightmares.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When structures overlay reality, the opportunists take advantage of these structures. We know these people now, the people that have mastered the social web. They understand what it takes to make us tick, to make us react and pay attention. They know how to to mold us. We’ve given them the data to do so. Volunteering the key to our collective psyche.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over time, the opportunists have woven themselves into our data centers. They’re now nested in the sharp frameworks of the algorithms. The algorithms elevate them like knives to our homes where they’re unwelcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we pay attention for whatever reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The opportunists speak to the margins in our society. They summon ghosts of untruth lingering in the parts of our lives that we can’t quite comprehend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We don’t know whether to call them opportunists or activists or political players. We just know that they shift reality to gain power. They work their way into conversations we have on the web. They help to create margins where margins didn’t before exist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Opportunists from all directions equally swoop in to establish structure. Old conversations previously closed are now re-opening: race, evolution, religion, time, and space. The Enlightenment is more and more discarded as a temporary myth. The foundation of America is more and more seen as a failed experiment. Voices haunted by ghosts of untruth whisper that all people are not created equal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reality itself seems to be fracturing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We don’t like the web, but we exist within it because we need it. To communicate with our friends and family, to gain power in society, even to breed. We’re all in the fight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, none of us are happy with this, minus the opportunists. We’re simply adapting because we’re suited to adaptation. We’re adapting to be hyper-connected, adapting to the chaos, adapting to the new ghosts of untruth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At all times we’re exposed to the worst of mankind. Peace (or the illusion of it) is something of the past. With the worst of mankind, opportunists siphon ingredients to summon ghosts of untruth. To guide us in directions we had previously not considered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But why are we here, why do we linger with the opportunists and ghosts? Why can’t we rid ourselves of them?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s all too eerie. As we collectively experience each others experiences, the nature of experience changes. We are no longer unique, no longer capable of solitary reason. Truth becomes untruth because we willed it to be. Or maybe, that we’ve forgotten reason. With a collective psyche, we have no time to process memory or to make sense of experience. Myths are created to establish collective structure. With collective structure, our lives are failing to be uniquely lived. Our minds are failing to uniquely rationalize experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We may be evolving into something post-human. We may look back on our current situation and understand it as growing pains. Or, it could be that we are spiraling downward. There may be no future if all truth is made untruth. Time will tell as we continue to adapt our ancient biology to the modern web. Learning collectively how to rationalize truth. Knowing when a situation will be used by opportunists. And knowing how to extinguish the ghosts of untruth that currently haunt us.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Radical Sobriety For Moderates</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2018-06-02-radical-sobriety/"/>
   <updated>2018-06-02T04:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/radical-sobriety</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There is no perfect path in life. Rather, a path of mistakes, analysis, and gradual improvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The past few years I’ve stepped away from movements of all types to try to better understand my place the world. I stepped away from radical sobriety, from veganism, from social justice. I still identify with the two latter, although not the former.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Radical sobriety is a movement I miss. I’m not sure why it captivated me, but know now that it shaped my identity to the core.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time I graduated secondary school, I was addicted to Xanax. After breaking from that pattern, I’ve kept away from prescription drugs of all forms. Social situations have been difficult since and I’ve learned to adapt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;radical-youth-vs-moderate-adult&quot;&gt;Radical Youth vs. Moderate Adult&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Youth culture embraces sobriety. It creates sober spaces for radicals. Adulthood, however, assumes that we have broken from the ideological chains of youth culture. In place of youth culture, we have bound ourselves to the moderate chains of adulthood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moderation implies that you pay bills and generally do what is expected of you. Taking drink when those around you are drinking is one of those many expectations. Avoiding drink can even be seen as suspicious depending on your social or business circle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marcus Aurelius spoke of Socrates and his ability to moderate to meet expectations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Which is recorded of Socrates, that he was able both to abstain from, and to enjoy, those things which many are too weak to abstain from, and cannot enjoy without excess. But to be strong enough both to bear the one and to be sober in the other is the mark of a man who has a perfect and invincible soul.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, unlike Socrates I am imperfect. I suspect that Socrates was an outlier, perhaps even idolized to the point of near mythology. We can’t all expect to be like him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;imperfection-is-the-norm&quot;&gt;Imperfection is the Norm&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I try to abstain from activities that amplify my imperfections. There seems to generally be a better, more interesting path when intoxicants are out of the picture. The search for the better path is both the most difficult and the most rewarding part about embracing sobriety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We tend to associate with people contributing to the world in similar ways to how we contribute. The creatives associate with the creatives, the laborers with the laborers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contributing to the world puts us in touch with individuals like us. Contribution requires active, ongoing participation. Finding ways to take part in the world outside of intoxicants is difficult in adulthood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The City feels bound to drinking. Business feels bound to drinking. The myth is that drinking brings us together. The reality though is that we do not attempt to resolve the disconnect between ourselves and others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;rebellion-is-exile&quot;&gt;Rebellion is Exile&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contemporary Western culture seems bound to intoxicants throughout mostly all social circles. Rebelling against this culture as a whole is risking self-imposed exile. I find that the only type of rebellion that makes sense is to quietly fit in and make due with social situations as they are, where they are. There are no safe spaces for moderates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll refer back to my previous post, &lt;a href=&quot;https://uonai.space/writing/2018/05/29/fifteen/&quot;&gt;The First Fifteen Minutes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first fifteen minutes of social situations are the most awkward and difficult. At the bar, at home, etc.. This often leads to getting drinks as soon as possible. Note: The only thing that can make the first fifteen minutes more awkward is stating that you do not drink. I tend to order a fun drink without alcohol and avoid the topic of sobriety entirely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes it’s hard to relate to others. As we age, we become increasingly different from each other. The experiences that shaped us are rarely shared. It’s hard to break through the layers of an individual to find similarities. Without intoxicants, conversation requires creativity. This is a good thing, I think, because creative conversation creates lasting memories: Story-telling, jokes, games, active hobbies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When socializing, I try to find a few shared interests in the first fifteen minutes. I can usually find three shared interests, sometimes less, sometimes more. I’ve yet to meet someone that is unlike me in every way. With similar interests, there is endless conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not always easy to abstain, but it is possible to thrive while doing it. I’m not a radical and I’m not perfect. However, I do hope to impact the world by participating in it while protesting it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The First Fifteen Minutes</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2018-05-29-fifteen/"/>
   <updated>2018-05-29T10:16:22-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/fifteen</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Most creative tasks I engage in consistently have shaky starts to them. Take for example Writing and Coding. Getting into the flow is often more difficult than actually producing anything meaningful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find that the first fifteen minutes are the most difficult to get through. The process of staring down at a blank page, or a blank screen. Tuning out imperfection from the instrument and warming up the voice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These first fifteen minutes are the most uncomfortable and also the most introspective. The process of pointing the gaze inward and dedicating attention to a single activity. This period at the beginning of a task functions to me as the make or break period. If I can get through the first fifteen minutes of writing, I’m generally off to a good start. With enough free time, I’m then capable of going thirty to forty-five minutes more. Maybe even longer before risking burnout.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I treat these first fifteen minutes as a warm-up, like stretching or Kata. I dedicate as much capacity as I can to focusing on the task at hand. During this period I know that I won’t be able to produce anything meaningful. But know that if I can get through it, there is a chance that I produce something good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My most creative experience lately has been taking the first fifteen minutes of the day to write. I go to the kitchen where I make coffee or tea. I write freely as the sun rises through my windows pointing east. I can generally write a page or two if I’m lucky. If I can continue to write after that, I’m pleased. If not, and I burn out, then the writing exercise functions as a mental stretch in preparation for the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike writing, I can’t code first thing in the morning. And I can’t force myself to. It almost makes me ill to look at a computer screen before 9AM. Generally, on the computer I’m the most productive at night, sometime after dinner. I sit for fifteen minutes in my IDE and stare at the problem. Sometimes refactor some code to get familiar with the task at hand. Then get to work and fix the problem if I can avoid social media and distractions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the first fifteen minutes are difficult, I’ve found that there are workarounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Timers help to set linear structure. If I’m struggling, I’ll set a timer for anywhere between forty-five minutes to one hour. That ensures that I can sit an adequate time with the task to make at least some progress. I’ll often forget about the timer and realize only when it rings that I’ve made progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the designated time period, I’ll step away so as not to burn out. Productivity feels empty and meaningless if I’m not enjoying what I’m doing. I don’t get too involved in what I’m producing, as long as I’m making progress and setting aside time each day.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Installation and Configuration of Arch Linux</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2018-05-27-archlinux/"/>
   <updated>2018-05-27T05:16:22-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/archlinux</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://uonai.space/images/arch-linux.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Arch Linux&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;
I bricked my Macbook Pro this weekend and took the opportunity to upgrade to a Windows 10 / Linux dual boot. I purchased a Lenovo T470 because it was rated well for both Linux and Windows and was built for buisiness-grade programming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Manjaro is the Arch Linux distro that I decided on &lt;a href=&quot;https://manjaro.github.io/&quot;&gt;https://manjaro.github.io/&lt;/a&gt;. Arch Linux has a reputation for being difficult to configure and hard to maintain. However, Manjaro provides enough built-in functionality to make installation and maintenance less painful. I’ll try to highlight my process for installing Arch Linux to make it easier for anyone looking to make the move. Note: I anticipate that everyone will have their own form of struggle, so be prepared to tinker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;step-1-try-out-your-linux-distro-before-installing&quot;&gt;Step 1: Try out your Linux distro before installing.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on past experience spinning up VMs, I opted for Oracle VirtualBox. This let me get a feel for a couple different Linux distros: Solus, ElementaryOS, Ubuntu, Arch Linux.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Process for setting up VM: &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.manjaro.org/index.php?title=VirtualBox&quot;&gt;https://wiki.manjaro.org/index.php?title=VirtualBox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;step-2-back-up-files&quot;&gt;Step 2: Back up files.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I backed up the few files that I had locally by adding them to my Google Drive. Never know what can go wrong when installing new operating systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;step-2-free-up-space-on-your-hard-drive&quot;&gt;Step 2: Free up space on your hard drive.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My hard drive on my Lenovo T470 is 250GB. I dedicated 150 to Windows 10, 100 to Arch Linux. To free up space, I followed this tutorial: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9gS5SoogltE&quot;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9gS5SoogltE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;step-3-create-bootable-usb-drive&quot;&gt;Step 3: Create Bootable USB drive.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Manjaro has three versions: XFCE (minimal), KDE (luxury), GNOME (halfway point between XFCE &amp;amp; KDE), Architect (console-based). Based on my specs, I installed KDE. After downloading the ISO, I followed this tutorial to set up a bootable USB stick with the ISO. Because I’m on Windows 10, I followed this section: “Writing to a USB Stick in Windows”: &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.manjaro.org/index.php?title=Burn_an_ISO_File&quot;&gt;https://wiki.manjaro.org/index.php?title=Burn_an_ISO_File&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;step-4-boot-from-bios-run-arch-linux-installer&quot;&gt;Step 4: Boot from BIOS, run Arch Linux installer.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were a few Lenovo manufacturer issues that I needed to resolve here. I anticipate this will be different for each user based on manufacturer. You’ll need to modify your BIOS settings to be able to boot from USB. Here are the updates I needed to make:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;windows-updates&quot;&gt;Windows Updates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disable fast startup: &lt;a href=&quot;https://lifehacker.com/enable-this-setting-to-make-windows-10-boot-up-faster-1743697169&quot;&gt;https://lifehacker.com/enable-this-setting-to-make-windows-10-boot-up-faster-1743697169&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bios-updates&quot;&gt;BIOS Updates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I needed to make these updates to BIOS when I rebooted my PC. Prior to making these updates I was not able to boot from USB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SECURITY page
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Secure Boot = Disable&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;STARTUP page
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;UEFI/Legacy Boot = Both&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;UEFI/Legacy Boot / UEFI/Legacy Boot Priority = UEFI First&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Boot device list F12 Option = Enabled&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once manufacturer issues are resolved (if you end up having any), you’ll be able to install Manjaro. For the install, I followed this tutorial: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4-kafKduFZw&quot;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4-kafKduFZw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;step-5-install-packages&quot;&gt;Step 5: Install packages.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After installation was complete, I started installing packages for my dev environment. Mostly all packages in Arch Linux are installed through Pacman: &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.archlinux.org/index.php/pacman&quot;&gt;https://wiki.archlinux.org/index.php/pacman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To search for packages, the library can be browsed: &lt;a href=&quot;https://aur.archlinux.org/&quot;&gt;https://aur.archlinux.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the most part I’m happy with the libraries that are offered. Coming from a Windows and Mac background, I still prefer NPM for managing packages so I installed NPM I followed this tutorial: &lt;a href=&quot;https://computingforgeeks.com/install-latet-nodejs-and-npm-on-centos-7-ubuntu-16-04-arch-linux-macos/&quot;&gt;https://computingforgeeks.com/install-latet-nodejs-and-npm-on-centos-7-ubuntu-16-04-arch-linux-macos/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To install NPM from command prompt, run this command: $ sudo pacman -S nodejs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Software I’m running currently:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Visual Studio Code: &lt;a href=&quot;https://code.visualstudio.com/&quot;&gt;https://code.visualstudio.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Left: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/hundredrabbits/Left&quot;&gt;https://github.com/hundredrabbits/Left&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Firefox Nightly: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/channel/desktop/&quot;&gt;https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/channel/desktop/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hyper: &lt;a href=&quot;https://hyper.is/&quot;&gt;https://hyper.is/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Android Studio: &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/&quot;&gt;https://developer.android.com/studio/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve spent one day so far with Arch Linux and I’m pleased with the setup. Arch Linux brings me back to the DeviantArt Windows 2000 era when everything seemed customizable. Computing is downright fun with Arch Linux and I look forward to continuing to test its potential.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Eudaimonia and the Path to Happiness</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2018-05-25-eudaimonia/"/>
   <updated>2018-05-25T05:16:22-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/eudaimonia</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My first year of college, I met up with a friend at Tate Street Coffee shop. Tate Street Coffee was on the outskirts of campus on a small street packed with bookstores, boutiques,and diners. We met to discuss the topic “on how to achieve happiness.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We both brought notebooks. Sitting at a table, we attempted to break down the ontology and point to the root causes. After some time we ended at an imperfect conclusion. Namely, that achieving happiness meant pursuing your dreams while maintaining relationships with others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That conclusion was nearly ten years ago and since then I’ve often thought about this topic. Lately I’ve adopted the term Eudaimonia to refer to general well-being and happiness. “Eu” meaning “well”, “daimon” meaning “guardian spririt”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Socrates often referred to Eudaimonia as being essential for the good life. However, provided a double edged sword: Eudaimonia could not be achieved by the pursuit of happiness, but rather was a side effect of pursuit of what was right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quoting from &lt;a href=&quot;https://philosophy.lander.edu/ethics/socrates.html&quot;&gt;Lander.edu&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;One’s true happiness is promoted by doing what is right.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;When your true utility is served (by tending your soul), you are achieving happiness. Happiness is evident only in terms of a long-term effect on the soul.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The Socratic ethics has a  teleological character — consequently, a mechanistic explanation of human behavior is mistaken. Human action aims toward the good in accordance with purpose in nature.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Socrates suggested that doing what was naturally right, for long periods of time, would lead to Eudaimonia. Sticking to ethical principles by the way of virtue paved a path for the good life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Virtue is and always has been a hotly debated topic. It seems, rightly so, that everyone has their own virtues they value and subscribe to. Mine have shifted over time and I imagine yours have too. That’s learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nowadays I lean on Stoicism along with a few other systems of being.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stoicism has yet to fail me. All other ethical principles have failed me, sometimes drastically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stoicism was founded on four virtues, each learned over time by the individual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wisdom - understanding how to act and feel correctly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Courage - acting correctly in dangerous situations.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Self Control - acting correctly in situations around lust, desire, appetite.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Justice - acting benevolently toward others where it makes sense.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These four virtues can take a lifetime to learn. It’s said to be in the act of learning and acting on these virtues that the individual grows with Eudaimonia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Acting correctly on a virtue is often forgotten as it was the right thing to do. Acting incorrectly on a virtue, however is often immortalized. Society makes examples of individuals that act without virtue. Stoicism prepares the individual for this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we’re growing in Wisdom, Courage, Self Control, and Justice, we’re meant to fail. Stoicism embraces this constant failure. I think Marcus Aurelius said it best in his meditations. We endure pain and celebrate our struggle with Eudaimonia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Does what’s happened keep you from acting with justice, generosity, self-control, sanity, prudence, honesty, humility, straightforwardness, and all other qualities that allow a person’s nature to fulfill itself? So remember this principle when something threatens to cause you pain: the thing itself was no misfortune at all; to endure it and prevail is great good fortune.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It isn’t often nowadays that I get to discuss topics like these in coffee shops. Speculation like this often happens more and more on a deeply personal level. Life has a way of teaching us virtues whether we plan for their teaching or not. I anticipate that because as I have aged, and everyone around me has aged, we are at different points in our journey. Either those conversations are behind us, or our knowledge of virtues are so deeply embedded they can’t be put into words.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Project: Banxre, a Simple NodeJS API</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2018-05-24-banxre/"/>
   <updated>2018-05-24T05:16:22-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/banxre</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In my current project building out an IoT Hub in Azure, there was a necessity to bootstrap and scale an API with mock JSON as the API was being built. Starting with a boilerplate JSON Server, Banxre added additional features to make the JSON Server framework modular and scalable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JSON Server out of the box requires all JSON to be included in one file. This meant that i’d be maintaining a file of 20K+ lines. In order to scale the application and break it into reusable segments, the application structure was refactored into an /API/ folder to include all of the necessary JSON. To ensure that the application could deploy to Azure, a startup file was included to do the bulk of the startup work – server.js.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the application is booted, all files in the /API/ folder are compiled into a single database file that is then watched by the application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;View source code at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/uonai/Banxre&quot;&gt;https://github.com/uonai/Banxre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Designing in Shifting Sands</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2017-09-04-shifting-sands/"/>
   <updated>2017-09-04T05:16:22-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/shifting-sands</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We feel we are capable of creating perfect things. Many of us chase this idea our entire lives. Chasing this gives us a sense of satisfaction and lets us create long term goals for ourselves. Gauging ourself against the goal of creating the “perfect thing” shapes who we are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite being the pursuit of perfection, we’ll never be able to meet this goal. None of us will ever be able to identify all imperfections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we design, we take into account evolving ideas and theories. We take into account shifting time and shifting spaces. We’re never able to truly identify what perfection is, but we come close. In digital spaces, I find this especially clear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read more at &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@colinmccaleb/designing-in-shifting-sands-243cd6edee5e&quot; title=&quot;Medium&quot;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Future Storefronts and Digital Interfaces</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2017-08-29-future-storefronts/"/>
   <updated>2017-08-29T05:16:22-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/future-storefronts</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Online spaces are changing at rapid paces. We’re beginning to design web experiences that keep people engaged for hours each day. Interfaces react to user interactions and from these interactions we receive digital identities. Corporations based entirely on the web have spread across the globe. To keep up, it’s time to shift to new ways of thinking about how we do digital design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More at &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@colinmccaleb/future-storefronts-and-digital-interfaces-d232d0694e5e&quot;&gt;Medium Post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Aggregating JSON Feeds From Multiple Systems</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2017-06-15-integrating-systems/"/>
   <updated>2017-06-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/integrating-systems</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last month I solved a problem World Bicycle Relief was struggling with for a long time – integrating all of our international donation feeds into one single feed to show the impact with a campaign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generally when we launch a campaign, it starts as a US initiative and gradually changes into an international initiative that accepts currencies throughout Europe. We’d had now way to show that until now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The landing page is here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldbicyclerelief.org/en/cyclofemme/&quot;&gt;https://worldbicyclerelief.org/en/cyclofemme/&lt;/a&gt;
The technologies used on the page are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Javascript &amp;amp; JQuery&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;HTML&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CSS&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PHP&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;JSON&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Feeds from Various Platforms (Causevox + Altruja)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The code looks like this. When it runs, it loops into each individual JSON endpoint and pulls the funds raised. We then divide this number by the amount of bikes this produces for each currency. This number is populated on the page. The final step is taking this number and running it up to a grand total.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$(function () {
    $.when(
      //this is for US microsite
        $.ajax({
            dataType: &quot;jsonp&quot;,
            url: &quot;https://cyclofemme.causevox.com/api_endpoint/info&quot;,
            success: function (data) {
              console.log(data);
                var campaignfirst =Math.round(data.funds_raised);
                $(&quot;.campaignfirst&quot;).html(campaignfirst);
            }
        }),
  //this is for UK team within UK microsite
        $.ajax({
            dataType: &quot;jsonp&quot;,
            url: &quot;https://worldbicyclereliefuk.causevox.com/api_endpoint/teams&quot;,
            success: function (data) {
              console.log(data);
                var campaignsecond = Math.round(data[6].funds_raised);
                $(&quot;.campaignsecond&quot;).html(campaignsecond);
            }
    
        }),
  //this is for Altruja Team within Altruja page
         $.ajax({
            dataType: &quot;jsonp&quot;,
            url: &quot;https://www.altruja.de/api/page/YG1A?details=1&amp;amp;num=10&amp;amp;ort=1&amp;amp;callback&quot;,
            success: function (data) {

              console.log(data);
		var altrujaFundraiser = data.page.collected.replace(/\./g,'').slice(0,-2);
                //var altrujaFundraiser = data.page.collected.replace(/\./g,'').slice(0, -3);
                $(&quot;.altrujaFundraiser&quot;).html(altrujaFundraiser);
            }
        }),
//this is for Canada team within Canada microsite
           $.ajax({
            dataType: &quot;jsonp&quot;,
            url: &quot;https://fundraisecanada.causevox.com/api_endpoint/teams&quot;,
            success: function (data) {

              console.log(data);

                var teamCanada = parseInt(data[8].funds_raised);
                $(&quot;.teamCanada&quot;).html(teamCanada);
            }
        }),
//this is for Australia team within Australia microsite
          $.ajax({
            dataType: &quot;jsonp&quot;,
            url: &quot;https://fundraiseau.causevox.com/api_endpoint/teams&quot;,
            success: function (data) {

              console.log(data);

                var teamAustralia = parseInt(data[0].funds_raised);
                $(&quot;.teamAustralia&quot;).html(teamAustralia);
            }
        })

//assign the above three functions as a, b, and c. from there, they are referenced in the
    ).done(function (a, b, c, d, e) {
        var total = +Math.round(a[0].funds_raised / 147) + +Math.round(b[0][6].funds_raised / 95)  + +Math.round(c[0].page.collected.replace(/\./g,'').slice(0, -2) / 100) + +Math.round(d[0][8].funds_raised / 147) +Math.round(e[0][0].funds_raised / 195)
        $('.ticker').append(total);
    });
});
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Web is an Impossible Place</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2016-12-20-web-is-an-impossible-place/"/>
   <updated>2016-12-20T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/web-is-an-impossible-place</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest causes of fear in web developers is our perceived lack of knowledge. Taking a brief look at the web, it’s easy to see a lot of what we don’t know, and not a lot of what we do know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We don’t know what we don’t know and we can’t get any knowledge not knowing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More at &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@colinmccaleb/the-web-is-an-impossible-place-5cd4348277ca#.ahnotkc7w&quot;&gt;Medium Post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Project: World Bicycle Relief’s Year End Appeal Landing Page Build</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2016-12-09-year-end-appeal/"/>
   <updated>2016-12-09T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/year-end-appeal</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;December of each year, World Bicycle Relief puts together a year end campaign to collect the final funds to set up bicycling infrastructure in rural Africa.
After we shot a series of videos and photos on the spot and edited them down, I was tasked with building the landing page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More at &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@colinmccaleb/world-bicycle-reliefs-year-end-appeal-landing-page-build-a8c0dd58969f#.n4eb0kepg&quot;&gt;Medium Post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
